## **CHIRAG PATEL**

E-mail: chirag.chiragpatel@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 8849 597 473 | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chirag357/

### **Executive Summary**

Chirag is an accomplished sales manager recognized for contributions to record-setting sales figures, territory expansion and new account development. He has a track record of achieving targets in B2B and B2C markets. He has achieved transferrable skill set as a key sales team member and worked in several sectors including digital transformation services (IT), engineering capital machinery (Pharma & Food Industry), healthcare (IT SaaS/Cloud), asset management (IT SaaS/Cloud), building & construction and financial services industries. Offers an in-depth understanding of the sales cycle process and remain focused on customer satisfaction throughout all stages to achieve revenue gains.

### **Skills Summary**

- Account management & client retention
- Consultative & solution-based selling
- Well versed with complex technologies
- Business development, sales & marketing
- Stakeholder management
- Negotiation and proposals

### **Professional Experience**

## Prowerse Technology, Ahmedabad - India Principal Sales Consultant (International Sales - Europe)

March 2021 - Present Sales

Prowerse is technology services company which transforms on premises infrastructure to multi cloud set up. **Responsibilities & Achievements:** 

- Pursed new business and capitalized on emerging market trends increased sales by 40%.
- Managed existing customer relationships, built rapport and trust; grew additional revenues through up/cross selling.
- Demonstrated product offerings and value proposition to key decision makers to win new business.
- Coordinated with internal stakeholders to ensure executions are on time.
- Managed and nurtured customers and developed strategies to win new business via referrals in international markets.

# Kevision Systems (Kevin Group), Ahmedabad - India Sales/Business Development Manager (International Sales - Egypt & Russia)

July 2019 - March 2021

Kevision Systems is an engineering capital equipment company. They manufacture automated machines installed on the production line for anti-counterfeiting solutions for brand protection; Track and Track/ Serialization and machine vision inspection systems to conducted Q&A analysis for their products before & after packaging. These specialized and high

## equipped machines are intensely driven with mechanical, technical, electrical and software (SaaS/Cloud) verticals. **Responsibilities & Achievements:**

- Created and drove strategies to increase revenues within the assigned region. \*Average size of
   USD \$30,000 per project.
- Developed and executed business plans to increased sales.
- Demonstrated product offerings and ROI to key decision makers and C level executive to win new business. Gained indepth technical and product knowledge working along with cross-functional teams; mechanical, technical, electrical and IT software.
- Developed new agent base/business partners in the assigned region, generated new leads from international trade shows/fairs and demonstrated presentation to new customers.
- Managed and nurtured existing customers and developed strategies to win new business.
- Worked along with the marketing team for brand awareness and development.

# Healthnotes (HN), Melbourne (Australia) Sr. Account/Customer Success Manager

August 2016 - July 2019 Sales

Healthnotes is software as a service (SaaS) provider which enables over 3500 pharmacies and 430 hospitals around Australia giving premium services to increase customer loyalty and medication management services.

#### Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Managed pharmacy accounts and offered competitive solutions with HN software platform to increase revenue growth. Exceeded sales quota of AUD \$250K to AUD \$360K.
- Coordinated with technology and support teams to resolve technical issues. Gained ability to work with cross functional teams to resolve complex customer issues and work flow processes for business productivity.
- Managed and nurtured key account of Priceline pharmacy portfolio with 90 pharmacies (Revenues \$140K) and took ownership to grow 330 pharmacies (\$360K) for 2017/2018. Additional revenues for HN grew to (\$590K).
- Achieved client retention and steered inactive accounts with new feature offering and educating clients on return on investment (ROI) of software to maximize growth. Gained ability to deliver with solution-based selling.
- Contributed to sales promotion campaigns working with marketing and sales teams for event fairs/conferences.
- Managed CRM system for client updates & communications, sales forecast and conducted monthly reports for sales objectives and strategies.

# Loc8, Melbourne (Australia) Account Manager

September 2013 - June 2016

Sales

Loc8 is an asset management technology (IT-SaaS/Cloud) software company. It's handy region functionality allows you to manage and locate your assets for better control and visibility.

### Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Managed and nurtured relationships with keys accounts and developed solution-based selling techniques; increased new customer base by 40% and increased sales by 160%.
- Managed customers to communicate the value proposition through proposals and presentations.
- Worked with marketing teams to develop go-to-market strategy and plan for conferences around Australia & NZ.
- Developed strong understanding of customers' specific decision making and purchasing process, understanding their business needs and objectives. Gained ability to present to key decision makers and C level executives.
- Generated leads from trade shows/event fairs and networking events.
- Developed and managed pipeline activity against assigned quotas and updated activities in the CRM systems.

# Saint-Gobain S.A., Business Development Manager

September 2011 - August 2013

Sales

Saint-Gobain is a French global multinational corporation with an ISO 9001:2000 glass manufacturing unit. They specialize in high-performance technology processed made to order Architectural glass for high-net-worth individuals.

#### Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Managed relationships with major accounts and key project decision makers for value added products. Executed
  projects on time which led to increase in brand value and new customer referrals.
- Achieved 200% increase in sales target in the first year with new product sales strategies. Gained ability to coordinate with technical and project teams for bid and tender proposals to win major projects.
- Organized and implemented presentations to potential clients and architects to demonstrate product performance and return on investment (ROI) on \$ value spent winning major projects worth \$2.3 million for 2012/13.
- Developed and managed relationships with distributors, architects, civil engineers, business/international project partners and fabricators for joint tenders and proposals. Gained ability to coordinate and negotiate with wide range of key decision makers and C level executives.
- Coordinated and managed installation to execution at project sites and gained ability to manage large projects working with cross functional teams.

## ANZ Banking Group Limited, Melbourne (Australia)

**April 2004 - July 2011** 

## Client Relationship Manager - (Institutional Lending (IL))

May 2009 - July 2011

#### Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Managed portfolio of 250 client accounts and provided outstanding service for their complex needs.
- Coordinated with credit and risk teams for analyzing client applications with preliminary assessment, set up of trading account and credit limit approvals.
- Developed key relationships with industry bodies and partners for smooth transfer of client's accounts.
- Developed outstanding ability to nurture client accounts, generate leads from existing clients and increased the portfolio base to 30% for IL Team.

## Migration Manager - Enterprise Services (Functional IT)

March 2007 - May 2009

#### Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Managed to solve complex issues within tight time frames involving numerous stakeholders. Gained ability to efficiently manage off shore IT teams to resolve complex system issues.
- Coordinated with business unit heads to manage medium to high-risk severity level issues. Gained experience to illustrate to business unit heads for justified times needed to resolve complex system issues.
- Managed vendors and agencies and suggested business process improvement ideas for business productivity.
- Managed smooth delivery of migration fixes for Hyperion and PeopleSoft systems (Oracle) for Australia, NZ, and UK business units. Gained ability to plan and manage migration fixes and deliver in tight deadlines.

## Settlement & Risk Manager - Margin Lending

January 2006 - March 2007

#### Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Processed daily reports using oracle, excel database systems and applications to deliver electronic risk reports to several internal and external institutions. Developed extensive reporting and data analysis skills.
- Analyzed and escalated daily & monthly reports, risk operation issues and exceptions to operations manager.
- Maintained weekly reports on risk, client positions and stock delivery fines and provide feedback reports to channel managers and client services teams.
- Advised operations, client services, and broker channel teams on compliance and risk issues.

### **Premium Sales Consultant - Premium Banking**

**April 2004 - January 2006** 

#### Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Analyzed client portfolios and coordinated sales leads to financial planners.
- Achieved the milestone of ANZ Online Saver \$200 Million in new funds with a team of 12.
- Advised clients of new account options while cross selling other banking products.
- Achieved STAR AWARD Premium Banking (2004/05) achieving 97% for client satisfaction.

### **Contract Roles (Various)**

February 2003 - April 2004

# Softouch Hygiene Products Ltd. (SHP), India Sales Executive

August 1997 - February 2000 Sales & Marketing

SHP is an ISO 9001:2000 Pharmaceutical Company, manufacturing ophthalmic and surgical dressing.

**Responsibilities & Achievements:** Managed and mentored 12 sales representatives to achieve team targets. Generated monthly reports for data analysis, product developments and promotions. Achieved team and personal targets and introduced new distributors to grow revenue based - increased sales to 35%.

### **Education**

Master of Marketing

Liniversity of Melhaurna Rusiness School (MRS)

Melhaurna Australia

University of Melbourne, Melbourne Business School (MBS)

Melbourne, Australia

Advance Diploma in Hospitality Management (International Student) 2002

William Angliss Institute Melbourne, Australia

Bachelor of Commerce 1997 **Gujarat University** Ahmedabad, India

## **Training & Courses**

- The Psychology of Winning Business (Consultative and solution-based selling)
- Landmark Forum at Landmark Education
- Facilitate buying sales certification

<sup>\*</sup>Note: <u>Australian (Passport) citizen & Overseas citizen of India (OCI card holder)</u>